<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natural Language Processing on Jeffrey Paul</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/natural-language-processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Natural Language Processing on Jeffrey Paul</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/natural-language-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Secrets of Raw Text: A Journey Through Word, Sentence Segmentation and Capitalization with Python (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/sentence-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/sentence-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Title: Unraveling the Secrets of Raw Text: A Journey Through Word, Sentence Segmentation and Capitalization with Python (Part 2) In the Part 1 of this article, we focused on training a Neural Network that can segment a raw sequence (stream) of text characters into words and we were able to achieve an accuracy of about 95% using some complex feature engineering. By the way, if you have not checked out the Part 1 of this lovely project&amp;rsquo;s article, you can find it here .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Secrets of Raw Text: A Journey Through Word, Sentence Segmentation and Capitalization with Python (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/word-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/word-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Title: Unraveling the Secrets of Raw Text: A Journey Through Word, Sentence Segmentation and Capitalization with Python (Part 1) Introduction In the realm of Natural Language Processing (NLP), engineers/data scientist can sometimes be faced with raw, unprocessed text which may present a unique challenge. Unlike structured or clean data, raw text may lack word boundaries, sentence boundaries, and proper noun identification. It&amp;rsquo;s a jumbled mess of letters that can leave even the most seasoned NLP engineer scratching their heads.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Secrets of Raw Text: A Journey Through Word, Sentence Segmentation and Capitalization with Python (Part 3)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/true-casing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/true-casing/</guid>
      <description>Title: Unraveling the Secrets of Raw Text: A Journey Through Word, Sentence Segmentation and Capitalization with Python (Part 3) Introduction The final piece of the puzzle is to capitalize the first letter of each sentence and other words that need to be cased (e.g nouns). This not only enhances readability but also provides valuable contextual information. By the way, if you have not checked out the first 2 parts of this lovely project&amp;rsquo;s article, you can find it here .</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
